flukecal.com 2014-03-29

# Privacy Policy | Fluke Calibration: US

**Last updated September 1, 2013**  
Fluke Calibration has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our commitment to privacy, and to ensure you are aware of our latest position regarding privacy. Please note that this statement is subject to change, so we suggest you refer to it any time you may have questions regarding Fluke Calibration's privacy practices relative to the web. The following discloses our current information gathering and dissemination practices for the www.flukecal.com website. For non-U.S. websites, please review their specific Privacy Statements.

**Information** **www.flukecal.com** **gathers**  
Fluke Calibration’s www.flukecal.com website logs IP addresses and browser types. Therefore, you can browse this site without entering any personal information, and remain anonymous during your visit. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information, and to help identify you. This site also includes a variety of registration and order forms that may ask for particular information about our visitors such as name, email address and demographic/product usage information.

Information gathered through these means are used to learn more about our visitors, provide them with requested information, and to also mail them future informational/promotional materials from Fluke Calibration and its sales/service channel partners. You can request to not have informational/promotional materials sent to you, as noted in the "choice/opt out" section at the end of this notice.  
An exception is the employment application form that is located within our Employment section of the site. Names received from these forms do not receive future informational/promotional materials from Fluke Calibration or our sales/service channel partners, and are kept on a confidential basis in our employment department for current and future employment opportunities. Details about the different means in which we gather information from visitors are detailed below.

**E-mail communications**  
To help us make emails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open emails from Fluke Calibration. We also compare our customer list to lists received from other companies. In an effort to be certain that we abide by customer requests we make every effort not to spam and avoid sending unnecessary communications to our customers. If you do not want to receive email or other mail from us, please adjust your communication preferences as noted below at Choice/Opt-Out.

**Registration forms**  
This site's registration forms require users to give us contact information (like their name, email address, and some demographic data). We use this information to learn more about our visitors, and to keep visitors up to date on new products, services and developments. In some instances, Fluke corporate family or its distributors may use the customer's contact information to contact the visitor directly.

**Order forms**  
This site uses order forms for customers to request information, materials, products, and services. We collect visitors’ contact information. Contact information from the order form is used to send orders and also to learn more about our customers. The customer's contact information may also be used by Fluke corporate family or its sales associates to get in touch with the visitor when necessary. Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services.

**Online surveys**  
Our online surveys may ask visitors for contact information (such as their email address), or other demographic or product usage data. We use data collected from these surveys to learn more about our customers, their likes and dislikes, and how we can improve our services and product offerings. Contact information collected is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Fluke corporate family or its distributors may also use the customer's contact information received in surveys to contact the visitor directly, if necessary.

**Employment application forms**  
This site includes employment application forms in the Employment section of the site. Information gathered through this form is kept confidential, not used for future informational or promotional mailings, and is used solely in the company's employment offices for current and future employment opportunities.

**Public forums**  
This site may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, blogs, social media outlets, and/or news groups available to users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**Links**  
This site may contain links to other non-Fluke family websites. As such, www.flukecal.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these websites.

**Security**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control.

**Choice/Opt-Out of Receiving Future Informational/Promotional Materials**  
This site provides users the choice to "opt out" of receiving specific communications from Fluke Calibration and its sales/service channel partners. If you do not wish to receive future informational or promotional messages and/or materials from Fluke Calibration or its sales/service channels, please send an email to: [webmaster@flukecal.com](mailto:webmaster@flukecal.com).

**Changes/modifications**  
This site also gives users the option for changing and modifying information previously provided. Please send an email to: [webmaster@flukecal.com](mailto:webmaster@flukecal.com).

**COOKIES**  
The Site uses cookies to ensure that you get the most out of the Site and so that we can tailor our services to you. Cookies are small amounts of information in the form of text files which we store on your computer. Cookies allow us to monitor website traffic, improve the Site’s usability and to personalize the content of the Site for you.  
We may use an analytics service provider for website traffic analysis and reporting. Analytics service providers generate statistical and other information about website use by means of cookies, which are stored on users' computers. The information generated relating to the Site may be used to create reports about the use of the Site and the analytics service provider will store this information.

**YOUR CONSENT TO OUR USE OF COOKIES**  
You have the right to object to the use of cookies. We provide information about our use of cookies on our Site in this privacy promise and through our [cookie information](http://www.quintessentially.com/cookie-info.html) page which is linked in a pop-up banner when you first visit our Site. If you do not change the settings on your internet browser to disable, remove or reject cookies, you are deemed to consent to our use of cookies on our Site. Please note that we are not required to obtain your consent to the use of cookies where storage of, or access to, the information collected by such cookies is strictly necessary for Fluke Calibration to provide the services that you have requested. 

If you do not wish for cookies to be installed on your computer, you can change the settings on your internet browser to disable, remove or reject cookies. For more information about how to do this, you should consult the “Help” section of your browser. In some but not all instances, cookies can be blocked in the future by selecting certain settings. Each browser you use will need to be set separately and you will see that different browsers offer different functionality and options in this regard. Please note that rejecting cookies via your browser may not be effective with regard to HMTL5 and Flash cookies (which are explained in more detail above). For information on disabling Flash cookies, please go to Adobe’s website [www.adobe.com](http://www.adobe.com/). 

Each time you revisit our Site your ability to restrict the use of cookies is subject to your browser settings and limitations at the time. Please be aware that if you disable, remove or reject cookies, some parts of our Site will not work.

**DISPLAY ADVERTISING AND REMARKETING**  
Our Site uses a unique tracking code to support Google Display Advertising enabling Google Analytics to collect traffic data by using our cookies. This is in addition to the data collected through the standard Google Analytics implementation allowing the Remarketing feature based on Display Advertising from Google. It is with this feature that we use Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online adhering to the [Google Adwords Remarketing Policy](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=143465) and its [sensitive category restrictions](https://support.google.com/adwords/answer/2549062/). We and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimise, and serve advertisements based on your past visits to our Site for 30 days.

**OPT-OUT OR CHANGE PREFERENCES OF DISPLAY ADVERTISING AND REMARKETING**  
Visitors to our Site can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customise Google Display Network ads using the [Ads Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/?hl=en). In addition, [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) allows you to choose how your data is collected and can be installed direct in your browser.

**Still concerned?**  
If you are in any way concerned about providing information to Fluke Calibration via one of the above forms or methods, we suggest that you refrain from contacting Fluke Calibration via these methods, and contact us via phone or mail. Complete phone and mail information can be found in the Contact Us and Where to Buy sections of this website.

**Contacting the website**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, please contact:  
Webmaster at Flukecal.com  
Fluke Corporation – Fluke Calibration Web Business Dept  
799 E. Utah Valley Drive  
American Fork, UT 84003-9775
